Raymond Yen

Solutions Engineer | Front-End Developer | Operations

New York, NY I rvy5009@gmail.com I 646-678-1190 I LinkedIn/Raymond-Yen

Summary

I am a solutions-oriented and innovative Software Engineer who holds seven years' experience leading the operations for a small business in the transportation industry. As both a Web Developer and Automotive Technician, I have an innate ability to self-learn complicated concepts and translate this to intuitive solutions for the teams I manage and the clients I support. I seek the opportunity to work in a collaborative, client-facing team that places consumer experience at the center of what they do.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.JS, Node, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Git, Github, RestfulAPI, SQL, Sequelize, Python, Customer Success, Management, Churn Prevention, Operations, Fluent in Chinese

Experience

Software Engineering Fellow General Assembly

New York, NY

11/2019- 3/2019

- Designed interactive platform to buy and sell stocks leveraging HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- · Leveraged React.JS and CSS Flexbox to build a clone of the New York Times website
- Collaborated with team of UX Designers to convert hi-fidelity prototype into Full-Stack website for local Flatiron Eatery
- Built a full-stack replica of Instagram's website using React.JS and Express.
- Coded and deployed fitness application to help users develop workout routines using React.JS & Ruby on Rails

Manager New York, NY Central Auto Inc 01/2013 -10/2019

- Managed a team of full-time mechanics and office staff to ensure efficient operations
- Developed and led trainings on troubleshooting, diagnosing, and repairing a wide variety of vehicles and models with a focus on exceptional customer support
- Delegated responsibilities to mechanics based on customer preferences, staff availability and technical aptitude; de-escalated high-risk consumer concerns
- Oversaw all operations and compliance matters including but not limited to PNL, staff-relations, government regulations, expenses, and relationships with third-party vendors
- · Consistently increased sales by 50% over a five-year period

Youth Language Program Teacher Beijing Foreign Studies University

Beijing, China

09/2011 - 09/2012

- Collaborated with and facilitated both Chinese and foreign personnel to ensure the satisfaction of students learning experiences.
- Designed and developed project-based curriculum and lessons using backward designing, scaffolded instruction and differentiation to engage young learners
- Responded to teachers, parents, and community needs including informal requests regarding policies, procedures, and programming for young ESL students

Education

Penn State University, State College, PA Bachelor of Science (Finance), *Summa Cum Laude*

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive (Certificate of Completion)